Guide to the Robert R. Gros Papers, 1771-1976
Department of Special Collections
Robert R. Gros Papers,
1771-1976
Special Collections M0214
Gros, Robert R.
39 items
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Robert R. Gros 1971, 1981
Biography
Robert R. Gros is retired vice president, public relations, for Pacific Gas and Electric Company. He is active in San Francisco civic affairs and often lectures on international relations.
Container List
- 1797, June 3Adams, John. als, 1 pg, letter to Josiah Quincy (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 1955, June 18Churchill, Winston. als, 1 pg, letter to Robert R. Gros (RRG) (Box 1, Folder 2)
- n.d.Cobb, Irwin S. Ms. of "Arise and Shine," one of the Judge Priest stories by Cobb. Handwritten with many corrections, 36 legal-sized pp. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 1933, Nov. 4Darrow, Clarence. tls, 1pg, to RRG, discussing Mormon religion and Darrow's opinions on the practice of law. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- 1963-64Eisenhower, Dwight D. Correspondence with RRG including 2 letters from Emmet John Hughes, 8 items total.(RRG letters are zeroxed) (Box 1, Folder 5)
- 1976, Aug. 28Hailey, Arthur. tls, 1 pg, to RRG re: Overload (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Hughes, Emmet John. See folder 4. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Jeffers, Robinson and Una (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1938, Oct 10Una, als to RRG, 1 pg.
  - 1939, Apr. 4Una, als to RRG, 2 ppg.
  - n.d.Robinson, work-in-progress ms written on two unfolded envelopes
  - 1922Robinson, ams "Suicide's Stone" Back of sheet contains tms "Beautiful Charm of God."
- 1807, Nov. 6Jefferson, Thomas. als, 1 pg, to William Taylor. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- 1859, May 27Lincoln, Abraham. als, 1 pg. to S.W. Fuller. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- 1771 Jan 29Louis XV. document signed, 3 pp. (also 1 pg., n.d.) (Box 1, Folder 10)
- n.d.Marquand, John P. work-in-progress ms, typed with autograph corrections, 5 pp (Box 1, Folder 11)
- n.d.Rogers, Will. written as a series of jokes by Rogers in response to request from his son and RRG to help them liven up a radio broadcast. (2 lines ams) 5 pp. typed on Western Union paper. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- 1938-1942Wright, Harold Bell. 9 letters to RRG, with 4 pp manuscript development (outline, first writing, revision, finished piece) (Box 1, Folder 13)